(缅因州  大赦湾  1985年)
儒勒·凡尔纳曾经写道
Jules Verne once wrote,
"把两艘船放在
"Put two ships in the open sea
风平浪静的大海上  它们必会相遇"
without wind or tide, they will come together."
我的父母就是这样相遇的
That's how my parents met.
就像两艘命中注定会相遇的船
Like two ships destined for each other.
没事了
It's okay.
别紧张  你刚才都没气了
Easy. You weren't breathing.
他们来自两个不同的世界
They were from different worlds.
但人生就如大海
But life, like the sea,
让他们走到了一起
has a way of bringing people together.
我正打算给你煎鸡蛋
I was gonna make you some eggs.
别把我的狗吃了  好吗
Just don't eat my dog, okay?
没事的
It's okay.
我给你泡了茶
I made tea.
来  喝一口
Go on, try it.
喝了会感觉好些
It'll make you better.
那么  你是谁
So, uh, who are you?
亚特兰娜
Atlanna.
亚特兰蒂斯女王
Queen of Atlantis.
我叫汤姆  灯塔看守人
I'm Tom. Keeper of lighthouse.
她从一场包办婚姻中逃离
She had fled an arranged marriage.
抛下了她的世界
Left her whole world behind.
但在我父亲的灯塔里
But in my father's lighthouse,
她找寻到了意想不到的东西
she found something unexpected.
而我父亲找到了他的一生挚爱
And my father found the love of his life.
四级飓风亚瑟
Category 4 Hurricane Arthur
将在下午两点后登陆
is due to make landfall sometime after 2:00 P.M.
叫亚瑟怎么样
How about Arthur?
飓风的名字吗
After the hurricane?
是传奇亚瑟王的名字  他也是个王  不是吗
After a legend. He's a king, isn't he?
他还不止如此
He's more than that.
他是我们两族能和平共处的证明
He's living proof our people can coexist.
总有一天他会让我们的世界团结起来
He could unite our worlds one day.
只有最强大的亚特兰蒂斯人
And the trident could only be wielded
才能使用三叉戟
by the strongest Atlantean.
亚特兰王凭借它掌控了七大海洋
And it gave King Atlan mastery over the seven seas.
三叉戟使他变得如此强大  以至于海洋都嫉妒他
It made him so powerful that the ocean itself became jealous
发动了一场可怕的地震来摧毁亚特兰蒂斯
and sent a terrible earthquake to destroy Atlantis.
亚特兰蒂斯陨落了  沉入了海底
Down it fell, to the bottom of the ocean.
但是  传说有一天会有一个新的国王到来
But, legend has it that one day a new king will come
他将使用三叉戟的力量
who will use the power of the trident
将亚特兰蒂斯重新联合起来
to put Atlantis back together again.
抱着他
Take him!
亚特兰娜女王
Queen Atlanna,
欧瓦克国王命令您
by the authority of King Orvax,
立刻返回亚特兰蒂斯
you are ordered to return to Atlantis.
亚特兰娜
Atlanna!
但亚特兰蒂斯从不忘却
But Atlantis' memory is long...
国王不愿放她走
And its king refused to let her go.
- 亚特兰娜  - 汤姆
- Atlanna! -  Tom!
- 我的武器  - 接住
- My weapon! -  Here!
他们的两个世界本就不该相遇
Their two worlds were never meant to meet,
而我是一段本不该相爱的爱情的产物
and I was a product of a love that never should've been.
你不必回去的  亚特兰娜  求你
You don't have to do this, Atlanna. Please.
不  他们总能找到我
No. They will always find me.
下一次  他们会派出一支大军
Next time, they'll send an army.
我必须回去  只有这样才能救他
I have to go back. It is the only way to save him.
救你
Save you.
在我的世界里
Where I come from...
大海会带走我们的泪
The sea carries our tears away.
在这里不会
Not here.
在这里你能感受到泪
Here you feel them.
等安全了  我就回来找你们
I will return to you. When it's safe.
有朝一日
One day.
就在这里  日出之时
Right here, at sunrise.
我们会再团聚
We'll be together again.
你要坚强  我的小王子
You stay strong, my little prince.
我永远和你在一起
I'll always be with you.
别让他忘了我  好吗
Don't let him forget me. Hmm?
(马萨诸塞州  波士顿海洋馆)
所有的生命都从海中孕育
All life came from the sea,
所以我们想要了解自己
so if we want to understand ourselves,
就必须回到起点来看一看
we must journey to where we began.
而现在  比起我们地球的海底
Now, today, we have better maps of Mars
我们更了解的是火星的地貌
than we do of our own sea floor.
过来  靠近点  快  小鱼鱼
Come on, closer. Come on, fishy.
- 快  快过来  - 小伙子们
- Come on. Come over here. -  Boys!
- 别拍了  - 快过来
- Stop that. -  Come on.
跟着大家一起走
Come along.
- 再见  小鱼  - 再见
- Bye, fishy. -  Bye.
我叫亚瑟  你们叫什么
My name's Arthur. What's yours?
- 你们饿了吗  我也饿了  - 瞧啊
- You guys hungry? Me, too. -  Check it out.
亚瑟在跟鱼讲话
Arthur is talking to the fish.
怪胎一个  亚瑟
Such a freak, Arthur.
- 住手  - 那你要怎么办呢  怪胎
- Stop! -  What are you gonna do about it, freak?
住手  别碰我
Stop it! Don't!
放开我
Let me go!
《海王》
(时至今日)
你是谁
Who are you?
走  快走
Come on, let's go. Move it.
快走  快点
Come on. Hurry up.
头儿  我们控制了船长
Sir, we've secured the Captain.
求救信号关掉了
Distress signal's disabled.
没人找得到我们
We're running dark again.
但他们已经知道了  你们逃不掉了
But they heard it. You can count on it.
我跟你做个交易  我不教你怎么当船长
I'll make you a deal. I won't tell you how to Captain...
你也别教我怎么当海盗
And you don't tell me how to pirate.
其他船员在哪里
Where's the rest of the crew?
他们的勇气只有不做无谓的冒险
Decided discretion was the better part of valor
并把自己锁在鱼雷舱里
and sealed themselves up in the torpedo bay.
我们名声在外啊
Our reputation precedes us.
是你名声在外
Your reputation.
这是你的胜利
This is your win.
给
Here.
我可不能收
Can't take that piece of junk.
这是你的挚爱
It's the love of your life.
我从没告诉过你它背后的故事
I never told you the story behind it.
这是你爷爷传给我的
This was your grandfather's.
他是第二次世界大战期间海军的第一批蛙人
He was one of the Navy's first frogmen during World War II.
他非常擅长在水中隐蔽
He was so stealthy in the water,
部队里给他起了绰号叫魔鬼鱼
his unit nicknamed him Manta.
可是战后  他的国家把他忘了
But after the war, his country forgot about him.
于是他回到了海里
So, he went back to the sea,
用他的智慧糊口求生
scavenging and surviving with his wit...
他带着这把刀
And this knife.
我像你这么大的时候  他把刀传给了我
He gave it to me when I was your age.
现在它是你的了  儿子
And now it's yours, son.
我们撞到什么了吗
Did we just hit something?
不  是有东西撞了我们
No. Something hit us.
头儿  外面有东西
Sir, there's something out there.
又来了一艘潜水艇吗
Another submarine?
不  我觉得是个人
Uh... No. I think it's a man.
不可能是人
That's not a man.
A队  去右边  B队  检查通道
Alpha, to the right. Bravo team, sweep the passageway.
我可以进来吗
Permission to come aboard?
海王
Aquaman!
动作快点
我为了救你们可错过了不少欢乐时光
我等你很久了
I've waited a long time for this.
我应该认识你吗
Am I supposed to know who you are?
我在公海上寻找猎物
I scavenge the high seas.
你是海王
You're the Aquaman.
我们注定会相见
We were bound to meet at some point.
就不要经常见了吧
Let's not make it a habit.
起来
Up.
爸爸
Dad!
Dad?
真不要脸
Shame on you.
你们自找的麻烦
Boys got yourselves into this mess.
就自己出去吧
Get yourselves out of it.
混蛋
Bastard!
爸爸
Dad!
等等
Wait!
帮帮我  他被压住了
Help me! He's trapped!
你不能就这么丢下他
You can't leave him like this!
求你了
Please!
你杀了无辜的人  向大海乞求怜悯去吧
You killed innocent people. You ask the sea for mercy.
(压载舱破裂)
快走  别管我
Get outta here! I got this!
闭嘴  我不会丢下你
Shut up, I'm not leaving you!
你必须活下去  才能杀了那个混蛋
You need to live, so you can kill that son of a bitch!
- 快走  - 不
- Now, go! -  No!
- 走啊  - 闭嘴
- Go! -  Shut up!
不
No!
该死的
Damn you!
走吧
Go.
我总是知道在哪里能找到你
I always know where to find you.
老习惯了
Old habits.
- 来吧  我请你吃早餐  - 好咧
- Come on, I'll buy you breakfast. -  All right!
你要我让他们帮你把酒装到吸管杯里吗
You want me to have them put that in a sippy cup for you?
为什么我能在水下呼吸
How is it that I can breathe underwater,
在酒桌上却还是喝不过你
but you can still drink me under the table?
这是我的超能力
That's my superpower.
一艘俄罗斯潜艇
A Russian submarine
昨晚被高科技海盗劫持
hijacked late last night by high-tech pirates.
这些海盗涉嫌
The same pirates who are suspected
与海军高度机密的
in connection with the disappearance of the Navy's
隐形潜艇原型的失踪有关
highly classified prototype stealth submarine.
现有未经证实的报道称
And a further development, we now have unconfirmed reports
是这位被社交媒体戏称为"海王"的超能力者
that the metahuman dubbed by social media as "the Aquaman"
进行了此次大胆的营救行动
was responsible for this daring rescue.
不是我
That's not me.
胡说八道  就是你  对吗
Bullshit. You're doing it, aren't you? Huh?
就像维科教导你的那样
What Vulko trained you to do.
我就知道你不可能永远袖手旁观
I knew you couldn't stand on the sidelines forever.
你妈妈一直都知道你很特别
Your mother always knew you were special.
别说了
Don't even start.
她相信你能让我们的两个世界团结起来
She believed you'd be the one to unite our two worlds.
别说了
Just stop.
不管亚特兰蒂斯有什么问题  你都会不在话下
Whatever Atlantis' problems are, you're bigger than them.
亚特兰蒂斯害死了我妈妈
Atlantis murdered my mother.
你不能肯定
You don't know that for sure.
我肯定
Yes, I do.
他们杀了她  因为她爱你  因为她生下了我
They killed her. For loving you and having me.
你心里明白
And you know it.
儿子  总有一天你不能再怪罪你自己了
Son, one day you're gonna have to stop blaming yourself.
兄弟
Hey, buddy.
你是电视上那个鱼人吗
You that fish boy from the TV?
好极了
Oh, great.
我是鱼人  有何贵干
It's "Fish man." What do you want?
我告诉你我想干什么
I'll tell you what I want.
可以和你合影吗
Could we get a picture with you?
你是我们这儿的英雄  兄弟
You're like our local hero, man.
拜托你了  拍一张要不了多久
It would mean a lot. Just a quick...
随便你吧
Whatever.
- 好  来拍吧  - 别碰我
- All right. Let's do this. -  Don't touch me.
好  很好  我们这样拍
Right, that's exactly right. I'm gonna go down here.
来了  大家笑一个
There we go. Everybody smile.
(大西洋某处)
他明白这次会面的重要性
He understands the significance of this meeting.
他会听你说的
He'll hear you out.
- 奥姆王  - 涅柔斯国王
- King Orm. -  King Nereus.
你挑的会面地点
You picked a meeting place
太接近陆地了  我不喜欢
too close to the surface for my liking.
你不知道这里是国王议会吗
You don't recognize the Council of the Kings?
亚特兰国王在位之时  七大王国是一体的
In Atlan's time, when the Seven Kingdoms were one,
我们的祖先会聚集在这里
our ancestors gathered here.
亚特兰蒂斯国王坐在桌首
Atlantis sat here at the head of the table.
泽贝尔国王  像往常一样  坐在他旁边
Xebel, as always, by his side.
咸水族  鱼人族
Brine. Fishermen.
那时候迷失国和海沟族还没有陨落
The Deserters and the Trench had not yet fallen.
失落国度还没有消亡
The Lost Nation had not yet vanished.
他们一起造就了世界上最伟大的帝国
Together, they were the greatest empire the world had ever seen.
但是现在  我坐在亚特兰的宝座上
But now, I sit on Atlan's throne,
被陈旧的法律和政治束缚着
shackled by archaic laws and politics.
而我们头顶上威胁的增长却不可忽视...
While the threat above us grows undeniably...
陆地人总是充斥着暴力
Violence has always plagued the surface.
他们会毁了自己
They will destroy themselves.
他们会先毁了我们
Not before destroying us first.
我们已经躲藏得够久了
We have been hiding long enough.
亚特兰蒂斯再次崛起的时刻已经到来
The time has come for Atlantis to rise again.
我们尊敬你  涅柔斯国王
We honor you, King Nereus,
我们邀请泽贝尔成为第一个
by inviting Xebel to be the first kingdom
加入奥姆王联盟的王国
to join King Orm's alliance.
说得好像还有别的选择一样  维科
As if you had a choice, Vulko.
根据法律  你必须征得四个王国的同意
By law, you need four of the Seven Kingdoms
才能掌权并发动攻击
to ascend and attack.
失落国度和迷失国早已灭亡
The Lost Nation and the Deserters have long perished.
海沟族只剩下怪兽
The Trench are nothing but animals.
咸水族永远不可能加入  而鱼人族都是懦夫
The Brine will never join you, and the Fishermen are cowards.
没有我和我的军队去说服他们
Without me and my army to convince them,
你的计划就会胎死腹中
your plans are stillborn.
但我知道你真正的目的
But I know what you really want.
一旦你得到了四个王国的首肯
Once you've obtained the pledge of the four kingdoms,
你就会成为
you will be ordained
海洋领主
Ocean Master.
那不过是一个头衔
That is merely a title.
我不是傻子  奥姆王
I'm no fool, King Orm.
成为海洋领主  你就能指挥
As Ocean Master, you'll be commander
这个星球上最强大的军事力量
of the greatest military might on this planet.
我是天选的领导者
I am the natural choice to lead it.
是吗
Are you?
有传言说还有一位天选之子
What about the rumors that there's another?
一个亚特兰蒂斯人  生活在陆地上
An Atlantean, living among the surface.
他也是皇室的血脉
One of royal blood.
你可以坐在亚特兰蒂斯的王座上
You may sit on the throne of Atlantis,
但你王座摇摇欲坠
but your claim to it is weak.
你怎么可能还想着要统一整个帝国呢
How can you possibly hope to unite the empire?
我母亲的野种甚至没来过亚特兰蒂斯
My mother's bastard has never even been to Atlantis.
他忠于陆地
His loyalty is to the surface.
是陆地人  拿起武器
Surface-dwellers! To arms!
你们的国王受伤了
Your king is injured!
我不是想发动战争
I'm not trying to start a war.
战争早就已经开始了
The war has already begun.
是时候让他们听听们要说的话了
Then it's time we send them a message they'll hear.
- 我没事  - 别走
- I'm good. -  Stop.
- 给你钥匙  - 谢谢
- Here're the keys. -  Thank you.
我们回家给你纹面吧
Let's go home and work on your ta moko. Huh?
要是你祖父还活着
If your grandpops was still alive,
看见你没做完纹面  肯定会狠狠打我们的头
he'd be banging our heads for not finishing it.
是的  但我们有的是时间
Yes, he would, but there is plenty of time for that.
先送你回去睡觉
We gotta get you to bed.
明白吗
Got it?
我一直在找你
I've been looking for you.
不不不
Oh, no, no, no...
我需要你跟我回亚特兰蒂斯
I need you to come with me to Atlantis.
我要告诉你的话
Listen, I'm gonna tell you the same thing
我已经跟那老海星维科说过了
that I told that rusty starfish Vulko.
不过对你客气点  因为尊重女士
Except nicer, because you're a lady.
不  谢谢  我没兴趣
No, thank you. I'm not interested.
你打败了荒原狼  拯救了亚特兰蒂斯
You defeated Steppenwolf and saved Atlantis.
那跟亚特兰蒂斯一点关系都没有
That had nothing to do with Atlantis.
你同母异父的兄弟奥姆王
Your half-brother King Orm is about to
就要发动对陆地世界的战争了
declare war upon the surface world.
数十亿的人将会丧生
Billions will die.
你我的族群都是
Your people and mine.
我们必须阻止他
We must stop him.
那你建议我们怎么做
And how do you propose we do that?
你是亚特兰娜女王的长子
You are the firstborn son of Queen Atlanna.
王位是你与生俱来的权利
The throne is yours by birthright.
阻止这场战争  拯救两个世界的唯一方法
The only way to stop this war and save both worlds
就是让你获得你应有的国王地位
is for you to take your rightful place as king.
你觉得只要我一出现  奥姆就会放弃王位吗
You think if I just show up, Orm's gonna give up the throne?
我是被你们处决的女王的私生子
I'm the bastard son of the queen your people executed.
相信我  我不是什么国王
Trust me. I am no king.
我同意
I agree.
那太好了  很好
That's awesome. Cool.
但是  不知为何维科很信任你
But, Vulko seems to believe in you for some reason,
所以我来了
and that's why I'm here.
维科已经找到了亚特兰失落三叉戟的位置
Vulko has learned of the location of the Lost Trident of Atlan.
童话故事  那只是个传说
Ooh, fairy tales. It's a myth.
不是传说
It's not a myth.
有了神圣的三叉戟  人们就会服从你
With the Sacred Trident, the people will listen to you.
你就可以获得你与生俱来的权利  废黜奥姆
You can then claim your birthright and dethrone Orm.
我与生俱来的权利已经和我母亲一同死去了
My birthright? It died with my mother.
但我可以向你保证  要是奥姆发动攻击
But I promise you this. If Orm attacks,
我会用你们对待我母亲的方式对待他
I will treat him exactly the same way your people treated her.
毫不留情
With no mercy.
(北海某处)
那艘潜艇几乎已经废了  但它完成了它的使命
That submarine was barely operational, but it served its purpose.
你的一个族人阻碍了我
One of your kind intervened.
他不是我们的一员
He is not one of us.
他杀了我父亲
He killed my father.
我们的交易已经结束了
Our transaction has ended.
我不要钱  我要海王
Keep the money. I want Aquaman.
爸爸
Dad!
Pops!
爸爸
起来  爸爸
Come on, Pops.
快  他没有呼吸了
Come on! He's not breathing.
让开  我来
Move! Let me help.
醒醒  爸爸
Come on, Pops.
醒一醒
Come on.
我还不知道你的名字
I don't even know your name.
我是泽贝尔公主媚拉·查拉
It's Princess Y'Mera Xebella Challa.
你可以叫我媚拉
You may call me Mera.
谢谢你  媚拉
Thank you, Mera.
天哪
Dear God.
是奥姆干的
This was Orm's doing.
最坏的还没来
The worst is yet to come.
已经设立了暴洪预警
There's a flash flood warning here
时间延长了几小时
that was just extended for a couple hours.
今天在世界各地出现了前所未有的景象
Unprecedented sights from all over the world today.
我们看到战舰和垃圾被巨浪冲上岸
We are seeing warships and trash washed up by massive waves.
海岸线上充斥着废物和垃圾
These extraordinary scenes of coastlines deluged with waste
这不同寻常的场景正在世界各地上演
and garbage are taking place all over the world.
几十年间产生的污染又重新回到了陆地上
Decades of pollution has been thrown back onto land.
许多人都在问这样一个问题
Many are asking the question,
这是自然灾害还是另有缘由
"Was this a natural disaster or something else?"
不  这不是自然灾害
No. This was no natural disaster.
是他们把我们的垃圾和战舰扔了出来
They threw out our garbage and our warships.
这是我们与亚特兰蒂斯人民的首次接触
This was our first contact with the people of Atlantis.
你又开始讲你那疯疯癫癫的亚特兰蒂斯理论了
There you go again with your insane Atlantean theory.
你完全没有任何证据  沈博士
You have absolutely no proof, Dr. Shin.
睁开眼睛看看
Open your eyes.
已经有一个亚特兰蒂斯人生活在我们中间
We already have an Atlantean living among us,
他的名字叫海王
and his name is Aquaman.
这是哪里
What is it?
维科就是在这里
This is the exact spot
给我上了第一堂游泳课
that Vulko gave me my first swimming lesson.
你必须把陆地上学到的一切忘掉
You have to forget all the teaching of the surface world
更深入地挖掘你亚特兰蒂斯人的本能
and go deeper to uncover your Atlantean instincts.
可我已经知道怎么游泳了
But I already know how to swim.
还远远不够
Not even close.
我们先说清楚
Just so we're clear,
我会帮你阻止战争
I'll help you stop this war.
然后就到此为止
But then, I'm done.
也许那样最好
Maybe that's for the best.
海洋不仅仅是我们的生命之源  亚瑟
The ocean is more than our life source, Arthur.
海洋就是我们本身
It is who we are.
慢着  你可以在水下说话
Wait, you can talk underwater?
我也可以在水下说话
I can talk underwater, too!
太厉害了
This is awesome!
我们能做的可不止是说话
Oh, we can do more than just talk.
作为亚特兰蒂斯人不仅仅意味着你能在水里呼吸
Being Atlantean means more than just being able to breathe water.
你的身体能够承受极端的寒冷和压力
Your body is equipped to survive the extreme cold and pressure,
你的眼睛能够适应黑暗
and your eyes adjust to see in the dark.
太厉害了
This is awesome!
维科  我什么时候能见我妈妈
So, Vulko, when can I meet my mother?
很快  小王子
Soon, my young prince.
等你准备好了  我带你去亚特兰蒂斯见王后
When you're ready, I'll take you to Atlantis to meet the queen.
我把我的船藏在了这里
I hid my ship in here.
听着  我才不要上这破船
Listen, I'm not getting in that thing.
要想去到我们的目的地  你就必须上船
Well, to get where we're going, you're gonna have to.
你的渔船在一直泡在三文鱼油里吧
Your fish ship has been marinating in chum butter.
我下船的时候肯定全身都是沼泽的臭味
I'm gonna come out smelling like swamp butt.
你现在比那还臭
That'd be an improvement.
好吧
Yup. Okay.
(亚特兰蒂斯王国)
在水下建一座桥有什么意义
What's the point in having a bridge underwater?
门桥是旧世界的遗迹
The Gateway Bridge is a remnant of the Old World.
也是进出首府的唯一路径
It's also the only way in or out of the Capital.
为什么不直接翻墙过去
Why can't they just go over the walls?
防卫牢不可破
Security is impenetrable.
即使他们成功躲过了守卫
Even if they did manage to evade the guards,
也不可能躲过水加农炮
they'd never get past the hydro-cannons.
人们总是想偷偷溜进去
People try to sneak in all the time.
好吧
Yeah, right.
那是什么
What is this?
海关及边境管制
Customs and border control.
别担心  我有外交通行证
Don't worry. I have diplomatic clearance.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
旧城里有安全屋
There's a safe house down in the Old City.
血统高贵的族人从不下到海底
The Highborns never venture to the sea floor.
我们到了
We're here.
这是哪里
What is this?
这个气穴是额外的预防措施
We use this air pocket as an extra layer of precaution.
只有血统高贵的族人才能在水中自由呼吸
Only the Highborns can breathe water as well as air.
而且还能把动物们挡在外面
Plus, it keeps the animals out.
它们会弄得很乱
They get kind of messy.
维科  我来了  老伙计
Vulko. Here I am, old man.
这么多年了  你终于得到你想要的了
After all these years, you finally get what you wanted.
亚瑟  真希望不是在这种情况下和你重逢
Arthur, I wish it was under better circumstances.
真不敢相信奥姆竟然袭击了陆地
I can't believe Orm attacked.
那还不是袭击
It wasn't an attack.
按照律法  他现在还不能这么做
Legally, he's not allowed to yet.
但是他破坏你们的陆地战舰是一个警告
What he did to your surface warships was merely a warning.
为什么
What provoked it?
奥姆国王和你的父亲被陆地人埋伏了
King Orm and your father were ambushed by the surface.
被陆地人  我可不觉得
By the surface? I don't think so.
他们现在还以为亚特兰蒂斯只是一个神话
They still think Atlantis is a fairy tale.
我也在场
I was there.
一艘陆地军舰朝我们开火
A surface warship fired at us.
现在泽贝尔和亚特兰蒂斯结盟了
Now, Xebel sides with Atlantis,
加强了奥姆手中的兵力
giving Orm a fleet big enough
让他能够强迫其他两个王国加入他
to force the other two kingdoms to join him.
如果我们要阻止这场战争  你必须推翻他
If we're going to prevent this war, you must dethrone him now.
我要和你说多少遍  我不想做国王
How many times do I have to tell you? I don't wanna be king.
你还不明白
You don't understand.
等他成为海洋领主  那就太迟了
Once he is named Ocean Master, it'll be too late.
他的权力
The power at his disposal
将会是你无法想象的
will be unlike anything you have ever seen.
我是从陆地上来的  没人会把我放在眼里的
I'm from the surface. No one is gonna take me seriously.
我都不知道该从哪里开始
Okay? I don't even know where to begin.
先从证明你自己值得拥戴
By winning the hearts and minds of the people
取回这个  赢得人心和民意开始
by proving to them that you're worthy, and retrieving this.
我已经有一个了
I already got one of those.
这个不一样  你没有
Not like this one, you don't.
这是亚特兰失落三叉戟
This is the Lost Trident of Atlan.
我知道这个传说
Oh, I know the story.
这不仅仅是个传说  这是真的
It's more than a story. It's real.
这是有史以来最伟大的武器锻造师
It was forged by the greatest weapon masters in history.
用波塞冬寒铁  为亚特兰蒂斯首位统治者
Crafted from Poseidon's steel for King Atlan,
亚特兰王所铸造的
the first ruler of Atlantis.
传说这柄三叉戟中
Legend says the trident
注入了能统治海洋的力量
was imbued with the power to command the sea.
然后这柄三叉戟怎么样了
So what happened to it?
这要追溯到一切陨落之前
To know that is to go back to the time before the Great Fall,
那时候亚特兰王还是统治者
when King Atlan ruled over all that was,
亚特兰蒂斯也还只有一个王国
when the kingdoms of Atlantis were one.
那时候科技进步  国家繁荣
It was a time of great prosperity and technological advancement.
在世界的其他角落还以为地球是平的时
We had unlocked the secret of unlimited energy
我们已经发掘了
at a time when the rest of the world
无限能源的奥秘
still thought the earth was flat.
但是我们的野心膨胀了
But we became too ambitious,
对权力愈加渴求
too hungry for power.
海洋吞噬了我们  亚特兰蒂斯沉没了
The ocean swallowed us, and Atlantis sank.
但是让我们的文明崩塌的力量
But the very power that collapsed our civilization
也为我们开拓了通往未来的大道
also paved the way to our future.
我们被赋予了能在水下呼吸的能力
It gave us the ability to breathe underwater.
于是  我们进化了
And so, we evolved.
退化的人则变成了野鱼人
Others regressed, became savage.
国王则在自我放逐中
And the king lived out the remainder of his days
过完了余生
in self-imposed exile.
再也没有人见过他和那柄三叉戟
Neither he nor the trident were ever seen again.
我们有一支考古小队几个月前发现了这个
One of our archeological teams uncovered this a few months ago.
这是一则能追溯到第一代王朝的古记录
It's an ancient recording dating back to the First Dynasty.
我相信这里面有亚特兰王给人民留下的最后的信息
I believe it contains Atlan's final message to his people
以及神圣三叉戟的所在之处
and the whereabouts of the Sacred Trident.
这上面怎么说
So, what does it say?
我们不知道  这所使用的科技太古老
We don't know. The technology's too old.
这根管子上有迷失国的标志
The cylinder bears the markings of the Deserter Kingdom.
你得带到那里  得到信息
You must take it there and retrieve the message.
亚特兰王安息之处的线索就藏在这里
The clue to Atlan's final resting place is inside of this.
边境护卫队  你因非法入侵而被捕了
Border Defense. You are under arrest for illegal entry.
不
No!
不能被人看到你在这里
You mustn't be seen here!
你肯定不想好好聊聊吧
I don't suppose you want to talk about this, do you?
我也不想
Neither do I.
我以国王奥姆陛下之名宣布  你被捕了
In the name of His Highness, King Orm, I place you under arrest.
欢迎来到亚特兰蒂斯
Welcome to Atlantis...
哥哥
Brother.
真不敢相信  你终于来了
I can't believe you're finally here.
我听了太多关于你的故事
I've heard so many stories about you.
这么多年来  我一直以我的父亲
All these years, I've been ashamed of my mother
委身于一个陆地人而为辱
for defiling herself with a surface-dweller.
以我有一个混血的哥哥为辱
Ashamed of the fact that I have a half-breed brother
我多想用我的三叉戟戳穿你的心脏
whose heart I wanted to run my trident through.
但你现在终于来到了我的面前  我承认
But now that you're finally here before me, I must admit...
我很矛盾
I am conflicted.
你想要冲突吗
You want conflict,
不如解开我的链子  弟弟
why don't you take these chains off, little brother?
我们就知道谁能笑到最后了
And we'll see who gets run through.
看来你带来了我们母亲的武器
Yes, I see you've brought our mother's weapon.
过去了这么久  你就是为此而来的吗
Is that why you've come here after all this time?
为了杀了我
To kill me?
我是来组织一个疯子毁灭世界
I came here to stop a maniac from destroying the world.
我知道了
I see.
你要怎么阻止陆地人
And how do you plan to stop the atrocities
一直以来的暴行
that the surface continues to commit?
因为这一个世纪以来  他们污染我们的水域
Because for a century, they have polluted our waters
毒害我们的孩子
and poisoned our children.
现在  他们烧红了天空  大洋也为之沸腾
And now, their skies burn and our oceans boil.
你花了这么大的力气
And you've come all this way
只是为了站在你族人的对立面吗
to take sides against your own people?
这种战争根本没有什么站边
There are no sides in a war like this.
你显然已经选择了自己的站边
You have clearly chosen a side
来这里妄图挑战王位
and come here to challenge the throne.
如果只有那样才能阻止你的战争
If that's what it takes to stop your war.
你要发起国王挑战吗
Are you invoking the Combat of the Kings?
随你怎么说  我看就是打你屁股
Call it whatever you want. I call it an ass-whooping.
那我们不如就这么办吧
Well then, perhaps that's how we'll proceed.
- 陛下  - 奥姆  别
- Your Majesty! -  Orm, please.
你们还不明白吗
Don't you see?
如果我在所有人的见证下
If I defeat the firstborn son of Atlanna
在正式挑战中打败了亚特兰娜的长子
in a formal challenge in front of everyone,
那七大王国
then all Seven Kingdoms
就必须承认我是真正的国王
will have to concede that I am the one true king.
陛下  击败无知者没有胜利可言
Your Majesty, there is no victory in defeating the ignorant.
你哥哥显然是个低能儿
Your brother is clearly an imbecile.
陛下  他不懂我们的方式
Your Highness, he doesn't know our ways.
那他就要被好好教育一番
Then he's about to get an education.
你要正式挑战我吗
Are you officially challenging me?
没错  我要挑战你  等我赢了
Hell yes, I challenge you. And when I win...
如果你赢了
If you win,
我将停止一切举动  战争结束
I will cease all immediate action. The war is over.
但如果我赢了
But if I win...
你就完了
You're over.
来吧
Let's do it.
那就这么定了
So be it.
挑战已经提出  我接受了
Challenge has been made, and I accept.
让他准备好上烈焰之环
Prepare him for the Ring of Fire.
等等  什么环
Wait. The ring of what?
你怎么能如此愚蠢地被奥姆下套进行战斗
How could you be so foolish to let Orm bait you into a fight?
我倒是觉得我解决了我们的问题
It seems to me like I just solved all of our problems.
我打赢他  战争就结束了  我就能回家了
I beat him in a battle, war's over, I get to go home.
你在陆地上是一名优秀的战士
You're a formidable fighter on land,
但是你在这里根本无法发挥
but here you're out of your element, literally.
奥姆一直都在水下生活
Orm has spent his entire life underwater,
进行作战训练  进行精英训练
training to be a warrior, training to be the best.
是你教会了我怎么战斗  眼镜蛇
You taught me how to fight, Cobra Kai.
看看你还记不记得
Let's see if you remember anything.
这大叉子是用来干什么的
So, what's with the big fork?
这是三叉戟  防住
It's a trident. Now, defend yourself.
这是什么东西
What the hell is this?
等你能熟练掌握三叉戟的用法  我会教你这一招
I'll teach you this move when you've mastered the trident.
这不公平
It's not fair.
这东西又大又笨重  我为什么不能用剑
This thing is so big and awkward. Why can't I use a sword?
那是你妈妈的三叉戟  皇家传统武器
That's your mother's trident. A traditional weapon of royalty.
只有你能熟练掌握  你才能成为国王
You'll never be a king until you've mastered it.
那她为什么从来不来看我
Why has she never come to see me, huh?
我说了  等你准备好
I told you, when you're ready...
不要再骗我了  我做了你要我做到的所有事
Stop lying to me! I've done everything you ever asked.
我每次通过一关  你就会给我另一关
And every time I pass a test, you make up another one.
我什么时候才能变得足够好
When am I gonna be good enough?
她不爱我吗
Does she not love me?
你妈妈爱你甚于这世上的一切
Your mother loved you more than anything in the world.
但是她必须要回到亚特兰蒂斯  才能保护你
But she had to return to Atlantis to keep you safe.
她和欧瓦克国王的亲事很早以前就定了下来
Her marriage to King Orvax was arranged a long time ago,
所以她必须要嫁给他
so she had to marry him...
给他生下一子  奥姆王子
And bear him a son, Prince Orm.
当欧瓦克发现了你的存在
When Orvax eventually found out about you,
他被嫉妒所吞噬
he became overwhelmed with jealousy
将她献祭给了海沟族的海怪
and sacrificed her to the creatures of the Trench.
你是说他们处决了她吗
Are you saying they executed her?
因为她生下了我
Because she had me?
我记得
I remember...
一切
Everything.
我有东西要给你
I have something for you.
这原本是我母亲的
It belonged to my mother.
告诉我
Tell me...
你觉得她会希望
Do you think she would have enjoyed
看到自己的儿子们互相残杀吗
watching her sons murder each other?
我明白你的恐惧和抗拒  媚拉
I understand your fear and your reluctance, Mera.
真的  我不想要战争
I truly do. I don't want war...
别想安抚我
Don't patronize me!
我了解你
I know you.
你所做的一切都违背了
What you're doing flies in the face of everything
我们年少时  你母亲教导我们的一切
that your mother taught us when we were children.
要是她还在
If she were here...
但她不在这里
But she's not here, is she?
我的母亲教会我们叛变
What my mother taught us was treason.
不要追随她的脚步
Don't follow in her wake.
好了  这是一个又大又古老的火焰环
All right! So, this is the big, old ring of fire, huh?
怎么玩  我就在这里暴揍你吗
How's it work? I just kick your ass right here?
维科
Vulko.
请护送我的未婚妻去皇家座席
Will you escort my betrothed to the royal box?
走吧  梅拉公主
Let's go, Lady Mera.
我们这里有一个关于卡拉森的神话
Down here, we have a legend about the Karathen,
那是一种强大的海怪
an ancient sea monster so powerful
连亚特兰王也要惧上三分
that even King Atlan himself feared it.
于是他将它关在海洋的深处
So, he imprisoned it in the depths of the ocean.
那个怪兽就在深渊中等待着东山再起的一天
And in that abyss, the creature bides its time waiting to rise again.
亚特兰蒂斯一直在等待
Atlantis has been lying in wait...
现在  这怪兽苏醒了
And now, the beast has awakened.
曾经  我无比地想要见上你一面
You know here was a time when I wanted to meet you more than anything.
我想认识我的弟弟
Get to know my little brother.
让他知道他不是一个人  我们有彼此
Let him know that he wasn't alone, that we were in it together.
要是我知道你会变成这样一个混蛋
If only I had known what a dick you would turn out to be.
我们的母亲是因为你才被处决的
You were the reason our mother was executed.
从那以后我就一直恨你
And I've hated you for it ever since.
但我不想杀死你  亚瑟
But I do not want to kill you, Arthur.
我要再给你一次机会
I'm going to give you one chance.
回家吧
Go home.
不要再回到亚特兰蒂斯了
Do not ever come back to Atlantis.
你赢不了的
You are not going to win this.
不管你愿不愿意  我们必要和陆地人开战
A war is coming to the surface whether you like it or not.
我要带着七大海的愤怒
And I am bringing the wrath of the seven seas with me.
你知道我不会放任不管的
You know I can't let that happen.
我知道
I know.
那是什么声音
What the hell is that?
烈焰之环
The Ring of Fire.
该死
Shit.
亚特兰蒂斯的人民  听好了
People of Atlantis, hear me!
我来自陆地的哥哥
My brother has come from the surface
要来挑战我的王位
to challenge me for the throne.
让我们用古老的办法解决他的挑衅
Let us settle his claim in the ancient way.
浴血方能明神意
By bloodshed do the gods make known their will!
叛徒
Traitor!
你永远成不了国王
You'll never be king!
没想到我能看到我的父亲
Never thought I'd see the day when my own father
在亚特兰蒂斯国王面前低头
would bow before the king of Atlantis.
陆地人先出手的  你指望我们怎么办
The surface-dwellers drew first blood. What would you have us do?
求他们饶我们一命吗
Beg them for mercy?
我和你一样讨厌陆地人
I detest the surface as much as you do.
但你不觉得这一切发生的时机有点太凑巧了吗
But don't you find the timing of all of this a bit convenient?
但是你没有那么好骗  对吗
But you wouldn't be that gullible, would you?
你也想要发动这场战争
You want this war too, don't you?
那些陆地人已经不安于待在地面上了
It is past time the surface-dwellers learned their place in the world.
如果必须要这么做的话  那只能放手去做了
If this is how it must be done, then so be it.
你有我们母亲的三叉戟
You have our mother's trident.
很强大  但是和她一样残缺
Powerful, but flawed like her.
我继承了我父亲的
I wield my father's.
这柄戟还未尝一败
And it has never known defeat!
我向亚特兰娜保证过我会保护她
I promised Atlanna I'd protect him.
这不是比赛  这是处决
This isn't a competition. It's an execution.
我才是唯一真正的国王
I am the one true king!
你还在等我要请你吗  快进来
You waiting for an invitation? Get in!
媚拉
Mera!
好吧  我们有什么计划
Oh, yeah. So, what's the plan?
计划就是找回亚特兰的三叉戟  然后挑战奥姆
The plan was to recover Atlan's trident, then challenge Orm.
好吧  那我们的顺序有点反了
Okay, so we're doing things a little out of order.
意外总会有的
Shit happens.
小心  六点钟方向有飞行物
Heads up! We got a bogey on our six!
- 这话是什么意思  - 后面有坏人
- What does that even mean? -  Bad guys behind us.
- 那就直接这么说就行了  - 后面有坏人
- Then just say that! -  Bad guys behind us!
等等  你说过我们不能翻过这些墙
Whoa, whoa, wait, you said we couldn't go over these walls.
- 是的  - 你说有水加农炮
- I did! -  You said there were hydro-cannons!
是的  闭嘴
I did, now shut up!
该死
Oh, shit!
Shit!
该死
我们还没死  但我希望他以为我们死了
We're not dead yet! But I'm hoping he'll think we are.
抓着这个
Here, hold this.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
- 听着  匹诺曹就是这样得救的  - 谁
- Listen, it worked for Pinocchio. -  Who?
没谁  过来  进去  快点
Never mind. Come here, get in. Come on.
太好了  现在我们要被吃了
Great. So we're getting eaten.
你到底是怎么做到的
How are you even doing this, anyway?
我不知道
I don't know.
我有时能懂它们说话  它们有时也能懂我
I can hear them sometimes, and they can hear me.
没错  因为你们都是又大又蠢的动物
Right. Because you're both big, dumb animals.
- 我刚救了你的命呢  - 我先救你的
- Hey, I just saved your life. -  I saved yours first!
它说"没有危险了"
She said, "Coast is clear."
那我们现在去哪里
So, where to now?
去一片被你们称作撒哈拉的沙漠
To the ocean of sand your people call the Sahara.
好
All right.
(西撒哈拉)
我一般不接受包租
I don't usually take charters,
但一般也不会有人付我海盗宝藏
but I don't usually get paid in pirate treasure.
谢谢你载我们  伙计
Thanks for the ride, buddy.
天啊
Oh, man.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我从来没有到过这么高的地方
I've never been so high up before.
或者离家这么远
Or so far from home.
但至少你还有家
But at least you have a home.
已经没有了
Not anymore.
我不能再回去了
I can never go back.
当我从竞技场里把你救下  我就背叛了一切
I betrayed everything when I saved you from the coliseum.
但你和国王订婚了  他们必须接纳你
Yeah, but you're engaged to the king. They have to take you back.
亚特兰蒂斯有很多优点
Atlantis is many wonderful things.
但不包括宽恕
But forgiving, it is not.
嗯  但你是皇室
Yeah, but you're royalty.
你母亲也曾经是
So was your mother.
如果我现在回去  我就会被献祭给海沟族
If I went back now, I'd be sacrificed to the Trench.
连我的父亲都不会接纳我
Even my own father wouldn't take me back.
往好处看
Look on the bright side,
现在你不用嫁给
now you don't have to marry
某个你根本就不爱的混蛋了
some tool bag that you're not in love with.
我的责任不是爱
My obligation isn't to love.
而是要为我的家庭和国家
It is to my family and my nation,
而我背弃了这两者
and I've turned my back on both.
有时候  你不得不做出正确的事
Sometimes, you have to do what's right,
即便你会因此心痛
even if your heart aches against it.
陛下
Your Highness.
追踪器显示媚拉公主在迷失国
The tracker places Princess Mera here, in the Deserter Kingdom.
你说她死了
You said she was dead.
显然没有
Apparently not.
那说明你哥哥也还活着
Then your brother still lives as well?
活不了太久了
Not for long.
穆克队长  马上集结先锋队
Captain Murk, assemble a strike force immediately.
不  必须逮捕媚拉并安全送到我手上
No! Mera is to be arrested and safely returned to me.
她背叛了王权
She betrayed the throne.
她是泽贝尔的女儿
She is a daughter of Xebel.
如果她受到任何伤害  我们的联盟也就此终了
If any harm befalls her, our coalition is over.
陛下
Your Highness,
我们正在进入鱼人国的水域
we are now entering the waters of the Fishermen Kingdom.
我们现在首要考虑的应该是
Securing the alliance of the other two kingdoms
维护和另外两国的联盟
should be our immediate concern.
我的宰相一如既往地正确
My vizier is correct. As usual.
逮捕他们  将涅柔斯国王的女儿毫发无伤地带回
Arrest them and bring back King Nereus' daughter unharmed.
我们到了
We're here!
这附近有东西吗
Is there anything nearby?
只有延绵好几公里的沙漠  伙计
Nothing but desert for hundreds of K's, mate!
- 只有沙漠  - 他错了
- Nothing but desert. -  He's wrong.
你干什么  等等  不
Hey! What are you doing? Wait! No! Oh...
她跳了下去  她都没有降落伞
She just jumped! She didn't have a parachute!
红发疯子  不得不爱
Redheads! You gotta love 'em.
该死
Shit!
你比我以为的还要疯
Oh, you're crazier than I thought!
这边
This way.
(印度洋某处)
你上次被打败了
You were defeated the last time
是因为你的陆地武器不够强
because your surface weapons failed you.
我们的不一样
Ours will not.
这是下一代亚特兰蒂斯士兵盔甲的原型
It's prototype armor for the next generation Atlantean soldier.
我们亚特兰蒂斯人最是理解复仇
Revenge is something we Atlanteans understand.
我的精锐先锋队将听从你的指挥
You will lead my finest commandos as your personal army
找到那个混血杂种
to hunt down the half-breed abomination.
我动不了他们  但你可以  他逃到了你们的世界
I cannot touch them, but you can. He's fled to your world.
杀死他和跟他一起的那个女人  我会给你报酬
Kill him and the woman he's with, and you will be rewarded.
杀死他就是我的报酬
Killing him is my reward.
权杖  还处于实验开发阶段
The crown jewel. Still experimental.
能将水转化成带电等离子束
Converts water into beams of energized plasma.
我觉得我需要更大的头盔
I think I'm gonna need a bigger helmet.
当初  这里还是一片内陆海时
One of the tribes of Atlantis broke off and settled here
有一支亚特兰蒂斯部族逃到了这里
when this region was still an inland sea.
当这里的水都干了  他们也随之消失了
When the water dried up, they perished along with it.
消失了  真是太棒了
Perished? Yeah, that's terrific.
我们越来越接近了
We're getting close now.
是吗  接近什么  快渴死了吗
Oh, yeah? Close to what? Dying of thirst?
你快要被当脸揍上一拳了
Close to getting punched in the face!
听着  疯子  我知道你还不知道这儿的情况
Look, Fight Club, I know you're new to how things work up here.
不如你看看周围  我们迷路了
Why don't you look around? We are lost.
你看那边  那是什么
You see that over there? Hey, what is that?
什么都没有  这里就是一片荒芜
Nada. This place is a wasteland.
是你把这一片荒芜当作家园的
You're the one who calls this wasteland a home.
这不是我的家园
This isn't my home!
不是所有的陆地都长这样
It's not like the whole surface looks like this!
不  当然了
Oh, no, of course not.
你们还有各种恶心的城市
You've also got disgusting cities
把废水都排到我们海洋里
whose sewers empty out into our ocean
还有一堆堆的垃圾山
and whole mountains made out of trash.
你们还有一堆大公司
And, oh, you've got great factories
只会喷废料  融冰山
that do nothing but belch out filth and melt ice caps.
好吧  知道了  听着
Okay. Point taken. Listen.
我们的确有不少蠢货
Yeah, we got some idiots running the show,
但我们也有好的方面  好吗
but we've got some good things too, all right?
我们有绿色的森林  高大的山丘和美丽的湖泊
We got green forests and big mountains and beautiful lakes.
你肯定会喜欢的  那就像是海洋宝宝
You'd love 'em. They're like little baby oceans.
你想激怒我吗
Are you trying to provoke me?
我只是说你不能看都不看就对一个地方下定论
I'm just saying you cannot judge a place before you've even seen it.
你反正也对亚特兰蒂斯下定论
You've judged Atlantis on far less.
不  你能不能停一下  不
No. Would you just stop it with that? No.
你那愚蠢的亚特兰蒂斯定位器
Your stupid Atlantean GPS
让我们从飞机上
just told you to jump out of an airplane
跳到沙漠中央  现在我们迷路了
over the middle of the desert, and now we are stranded.
如果你真的是下一任真正的国王  我们就完蛋了
If you're the next true king, we're doomed.
(迷失国)
真是太刺激了
That was awesome.
看看我找到了什么
Oh. Look what I found.
你找到的
What you found?
没错
Yeah.
看看这个地方
Check this place out.
真是太厉害了
This is badass!
这里是军械大厅
This is the Hall of Armory.
就是传说中亚特兰的三叉戟铸造的地方
Where the legends say Atlan's trident was forged.
我不再觉得那是传说了
I don't think they're legends anymore.
维科说得没错
Vulko was right.
这是真的
It's real.
什么都没有
Nothing.
当然不会有用了
Of course it's not working.
自从撒哈拉变成沙漠后
It's been sitting here collecting dust
这里就一直在积灰
since before the Sahara was a desert.
天
Man!
"自从撒哈拉变成沙漠后"
"Since before the Sahara was a desert."
谢谢你重复了我说的话
Thank you for repeating what I just said.
这里都干了
It's completely dried out.
只能说你什么都不想的时候
Let's just say you do your best thinking
才是你最机智的时候
when you're not thinking at all.
好  站着别动
All right, now hold still.
你要干什么
Hey. What are you doing?
我们需要水  你是最近的水源
We need water, and you're the closest source.
别动
Now, hold still.
瞎显摆
Show-off.
我也可以尿点尿到上面
I could have just peed on it.
亚特兰王
King Atlan.
这把三叉戟蕴藏着亚特兰蒂斯的力量
In this trident resides the power of Atlantis.
如果落入坏人之手  它将带来毁灭
In the wrong hands, it would bring destruction.
但是如果到了真正的继承者手里
But in the hands of the true heir,
它将联合海陆所有王国的力量
it would unite all our kingdoms above and below.
如果想得到我的力量  你必须证明你的价值
If you seek my power, you must prove your worth.
前往世界尽头之外的暗海
Journey beyond the edge of the world to the Hidden Sea.
从瓶子里寻找航海路线
Look inside the bottle for the charted path.
只有在真正的国王手中  才能真正看到
Only in the hands of the true king can he truly see.
我们不能让奥姆找到这个
We can't let Orm find this.
等等
Hey! Wait!
怎么
What?
我们不应该先写下来吗
Shouldn't we have written it down first?
我已经记住了  你没记住吗
I memorized it. Didn't you?
当然  当然记住了
Oh, yeah. Totally.
他说什么了
What'd he just say?
"什么什么三叉戟..."
"Something something trident."
"从瓶子里寻找航海路线"
"Look inside the bottle for the charted path."
这是我们的下一站
It's our next stop.
(意大利  西西里)
我开始觉得你其实喜欢这些陆地人了
I'm starting to think you actually like these surface-dwellers.
不能看都不看就对一个地方下定论
It would be wrong to judge a place I've never seen before.
我马上回来  哪里都别去
I'll be right back. Don't go anywhere.
显然  就在那座山的顶上有一座旧城堡
Well, apparently, it's just right up on the hill. A big old castle.
我刚发现了一件非常有趣的事
And I just learned something very interesting.
匹诺曹
Pinocchio.
你让我们逃生的方法
You risked our lives based
是从儿童书里看到的吗
on something you read in a children's book?
等等  是书里的吗  真不可思议
Wait, it's a book? How about that?
我是从电影里看到的
I got it from the movie.
涅柔斯国王  我曾希望我们的子民
King Nereus, I had hoped our people had evolved
不再认同那古老的思想
beyond that ancient notion
认为我们与陆地的战争不可避免
that war with the surface is inevitable.
鱼人的立场是
It is the position of the Fishermen
如果要让陆地人知道我们
that when the time comes to make ourselves known to the landsmen,
那应该是我们去教育他们  而不是毁灭他们
it should be to educate them, not to destroy them.
我钦佩你的雄心壮志  里库国王
I admire your lofty aspirations, King Ricou.
但是我怀疑
But I suspect
他们其实就只是一群懦夫而已
they are but clouds of ink hiding the heart of a coward.
岂有此理
How dare you!
拜托了  我恳求你
Please. I implore you.
你们国人都是傲慢的哲学家和软弱的诗人
You're a kingdom of bloated philosophers and flaccid poets
你们的海水污浊不堪  这让我恶心
whose waters have grown stagnant, and it sickens me.
国王
My King!
国王已死  他的后嗣万岁
The king is dead! Long live his heir.
公主
Princess.
请让你的军队做好准备  陛下
Prepare your armies, Your Highness.
我们马上进攻咸水族王国
We move against the Brine Kingdom at once.
影像怎么说的来着
What did the recording say, again?
"前往世界边缘之外的暗海
"Journey beyond the edge of the world to the Hidden Sea.
从瓶子里寻找航海路线
Look in the bottle for the charted path.
只有在真正的国王手中  才能真正看到"
Only in the hands of the true king can he truly see."
"从瓶子里寻找航海路线"
"Look in the bottle for the charted path."
天啊
Oh, man.
什么
What?
太棒了
Wow. That's awesome.
给我看看
Let me see.
但是要怎么知道往哪个方向看
Wow. But how do you know where to point it?
给我看看
Here, let me see.
最后一句是什么来着
What was the last line?
"只有在真正的国王手中  才能真正看到"
"Only in the hands of the true king can he truly see."
"只有在真正的国王手中..."
"Only in the hands of the true..."
马尔库斯·阿格里帕
Marcus Agrippa.
他是位伟大的将军  但不是国王
He was a great general, but he wasn't a king.
大西庇阿也不是
Neither was Scipio.
这些东西你是怎么知道的
How do you know all this stuff?
因为我老爸  他把我的历史都教给我了
Because of my pops. He made sure I knew my history.
这些人都不是国王  除了这个家伙  罗慕路斯
None of these guys are kings, except this guy. Romulus.
罗马首任国王
First king of Rome.
"只有在真正的国王手中  才能真正看到"
"Only in the hands of the true king can he truly see."
找到了  那就是我们的目的地
There it is. That's our heading.
什么  让我看看
What? Let me see.
我们做到了
We did it!
我这个低能儿还不赖吧
That's not bad for an imbecile, huh?
很不赖
Not bad at all.
媚拉
Mera.
"厌恶在深处等待并渴望
"Loathsomeness waits and dreams in the deep,
腐朽遍布于人那摇摇欲坠的城市"
and decay spreads over the tottering cities of men."
退后
Get back!
亚瑟
Arthur!
我命令你们退下
I order you to stand down!
媚拉公主  你被指控以叛国罪
Princess Mera, you've been charged with high treason.
你是谁
Who the hell are you?
这个或许能唤起你的记忆
Maybe this will jog your memory.
你是潜艇上那个人
You're the guy from the sub.
没错
That's right.
但现在我有亚特兰蒂斯钢
But now I have Atlantean steel.
叫我"黑蝠鲼"
Call me "Black Manta."
你以为你能逃得了吗
You thought you could walk away?
我不是告诉过你不要把这当成习惯吗
I thought I told you not to make this a habit.
你跑不了
You can't run.
你要血债血偿
You owe me blood!
你怎么找到我的
How'd you find me?
你这位女伴有几个想要盯住她的朋友
Your lady friend has people who like to keep tabs on her.
不
No!
快点
Come on.
大家都进去  进去
Everybody, inside. Get inside.
我会像你那么"仁慈"对待我父亲一样对待你
I'll show you the same mercy you showed my father.
把你像剖鱼一样剖开
And gut you like the fish you are!
(系统故障)
亚瑟
Arthur!
媚拉  他们在追踪你
Mera, they're tracking you.
什么
What?
他们在追踪你
They're tracking you.
亚瑟  坚持住
Arthur, stay with me.
亚瑟  醒醒  亚瑟
Arthur, wake up! Arthur.
你偷了一艘船吗
Did you steal a boat?
码头的船不是公用的吗
Are the boats at the marina not for public use?
不是  那是个人的
No, those belong to people.
那些人是奥姆的精锐先锋
Those were Orm's elite commandos.
但是带头的人  不是亚特兰蒂斯人
But the one who led them, he wasn't Atlantean.
我以前从没见过他
I've never seen him before.
我见过
Yeah, I have.
他和他父亲是海盗
He and his father were pirates.
他把他父亲的死怪在我头上
And he blames me for his father's death.
他们选择了一个危险的行业  不是你的错
They picked a dangerous line of trade. It's not your fault.
但感觉不是这样的
That's not how it feels.
当时我能决定他的生死  而我让他死了
It was up to me, and I let him die.
我本可以救他  但我没有
I could've saved him, but I didn't.
所以我树敌了  他差点就伤到你
And now, I made an enemy, and he could have hurt you.
伤到你的话就是我的错
And that would have been my fault.
他现在是过去时了
Well, he's behind us now.
我们应该担心的是后面的事
It's what lies ahead that should concern us.
航海路线带我们去的是海沟国
The charted path leads to the Kingdom of the Trench.
就是他们杀害了我母亲  对吗
Are those the same creatures that killed my mother?
对
Yes.
她被带去那里祭献给了他们
She was taken there and sacrificed to them.
那里已经变成了死亡之地
It's become a place of death.
我们对那里有什么几乎一无所知
We know next to nothing about what's down there.
我们应该回头
We should turn back.
我们仍然有时间警告陆地人
We can still warn the surface.
让他们做好准备  迎接即将到来的战争
Try and prepare them for what's coming.
回头
Turn back?
我从小就学会了不显露弱点
Look, I learned from a young age not to show weakness.
知道吗  我用愤怒和拳头解决我的问题
Okay? I solve my problems with my anger and my fists.
我就是个粗人  我擅长武力解决问题
I'm a blunt instrument, and I'm damn good at it.
但这一路下来  我就只有被揍的份
But I've done nothing but get my ass kicked this whole trip.
我不是领袖  不是国王
I'm no leader. I'm not a king.
我不擅长跟别人合作或者相处
I do not work or play well with others.
我不能让你
And I can't let you die
因为想把我变成我本就不是的那种人而死
trying to turn me into something that I'm not.
你觉得因为你是两个不同世界之人
You think you're unworthy to lead
结合所生  所以你不配当领袖
because you're of two different worlds.
但其实正因为如此  你才配
But that is exactly why you are worthy.
你是陆地和海洋之间的桥梁
You are the bridge between land and sea.
现在我看得出来
I can see that now.
唯一的问题是
The only question is...
你能做到吗
Can you?
目前还未能追踪到媚拉公主  陛下
The tracking on Lady Mera is still dark, Your Highness.
维科
Vulko.
我值得信赖的宰相
My trusted vizier
自从我父亲坐上王位起  就一直陪伴左右
who has stood by the throne since my father sat upon it.
战争即将打响  你有什么建议给我吗
Have you any advice for me as this war begins?
我已经给你了  国王
I have already given it, My King.
但我会一如既往地拥护你的决定
But I will stand by your decision, as always.
我的决定
My decision.
保护它
To protect it.
同时又背叛它
While you betray it.
你以为我不知道你的叛国行径吗
You think I do not know of your treachery?
你仍效忠于我母亲的私生子
That you have remained loyal to my mother's bastard son.
你用了多年时间
That you have spent years
来训练他夺走我的王位
training him to take the throne from me.
不要否认
Do not deny it.
我没有
I do not.
为什么
Why?
我是血统纯正的继承人
I am the pureblood.
我将毕生都献给了亚特兰蒂斯
I have devoted my life to Atlantis.
他根本不想与之有任何关系  你发誓效忠国王的
He wanted nothing to do with it. You swore to serve the throne!
我确实效忠了
I do serve it.
亚瑟虽然只是半个亚特兰蒂斯人
Arthur may only be half-Atlantean,
但是他已经比你这个国王够格两倍了
but he's already twice the king you'll ever be.
带他走
Take him.
但是要确保他能看到
But make sure he has a view.
这些到底是什么鬼东西
What the hell are these things?
海沟族  我们到目的地了
The Trench! We're here!
- 他们太多了  - 快进里面
- There are too many of them! -  Come on, inside!
他们是从深海来的
They're from the depths.
他们害怕光  给你
They're scared of the light. Here!
快来
Come on!
你准备好跳了吗
You ready to jump?
那边
Over there!
(海沟族)
那会把我们撕碎的
That thing will tear us apart.
我们别无选择
We don't have a choice!
亚瑟
Arthur!
媚拉
Mera!
(地心  暗海)
媚拉
Mera!
亚瑟
Arthur.
妈妈
Mom?
欧瓦克国王把我祭献给海沟族  但我活下来了
King Orvax sacrificed me to the Trench, but I survived.
我跟你一样一路奋战  最后到了这里
I fought my way through as you did, and I ended up here.
你一个人在这里待了20年
You've been here alone for 20 years?
是的
Yes.
来  在这里坐
Come. Sit here.
你一定要原谅我
You must forgive me.
原谅我让这一切发生
Forgive me for everything.
这一切都是因为你生了我
This happened because you had me.
不是因为生了你  没什么是你的错
Not for having you. None of this is your fault.
是我做出了选择  我必须离开
I made a choice. I had to leave...
这样才能救你  才能救你父亲
To save you, to save your father.
告诉我  告诉我他的事
Tell me. Tell me about him.
他...
Is he...
他还是会走到那个码头尽头
He still walks to the end of that dock.
每天早上都是
Every morning.
每天都是
Every day.
等着你
Waiting for you.
你为什么不回来
Why didn't you ever come back?
因为带你来这里的传送门不让我们回去
Because the portal that brought you here won't let us return.
三叉戟是回去的唯一方法
The trident is the only way back.
但是卡拉森在守护着它
But it is guarded by the Karathen.
传说中的怪物  是真实存在的
The creature from our legends, it's real.
它就在瀑布后面
It lies beyond the waterfall.
我们跟你一起去  我们可以一起战斗
We'll go with you. We can fight it together.
不
No.
它太强大了
It's too powerful.
多年来我试过很多次
I've tried many times over the years.
它只会允许真正的国王通过
The creature will only allow the true king to pass.
你害怕了
You're afraid.
是的
Yes.
很好
Good.
你准备好了
You're ready.
亚特兰蒂斯一直都有国王
Atlantis has always had a king.
现在它需要的不止如此
Now, it needs something more.
但是有什么比国王更伟大
But what could be greater than a king?
一个英雄
A hero.
国王只为自己的国家而战
A king fights only for his nation.
而你为每个人而战
You fight for everyone.
你不属于这里
You do not belong here.
我自开始
I have guarded the trident
就守护三叉戟  击退伪王
against false kings since the beginning.
一千年来
And for a thousand years
我见证了最伟大的斗士来尝试并失败
I have seen the greatest champions try and fail.
但我从未感知到任何像你一样不够格的人
But never have I sensed one as unworthy as you.
你一个混血杂种  竟敢来此
You dare come here with your tainted mongrel blood
妄图拿到亚特兰蒂斯最伟大的宝藏
to claim Atlantis' greatest treasure?
那就来吧
So be it...
混血种
Half-breed.
你以为自己有资格吗
You thought yourself worthy?
你以为自己是国王吗
You thought yourself a king?
你来此就是让此地蒙羞
You dishonor this place with your presence.
停下
Stop!
你说得对  我是个混血杂种
You're right. I am a half-breed mongrel.
但我来此不是因为我觉得自己有资格
But I did not come here because I thought I was worthy.
我知道我没有
I know I'm not.
你理解我的话
You understand me?
是的
I do.
亚特兰王去世后  就没人再能与我沟通了
No mortal has conversed with me since King Atlan.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是个无名小卒
I'm nobody.
我来这里是因为我别无选择
I came because I had no choice.
我来是为了救我的家园和我爱的人
I came to save my home and the people that I love.
我来是因为三叉戟是他们唯一的希望
I came because the trident is their only hope.
如果这个理由还不够的话...
And if that's not good enough...
那你就去死吧
Then screw you.
没人成功把三叉戟从亚特兰王的手中拿走过
No man has ever freed the trident from Atlan's grip.
如果他认为你没资格...
Should he deem you unworthy...
反正我很久没有吃过东西了
Well, I haven't feasted in eons,
我现在饿极了
and I am famished.
真正的国王
The one true king.
记住  咸水族是强大的野蛮之族
Remember, the Brine are powerful, savage brutes,
但是快速直接地
but a swift assault aimed
攻击他们的领袖  可以扭转局面
directly at their leadership will turn the tide.
打败咸水族国王
Defeat the Brine King,
你就能拥有这个星球上最强大的军队
and you will command the greatest military might on this planet.
今天  我们联合我们的王国
Today, we unite our kingdoms.
明天  我们将陆地夷为平地
Tomorrow, we scorch the surface!
崛起吧  亚特兰蒂斯
Rise, Atlantis!
消灭亚特兰蒂斯那群丑鱼
Death to the Atlantean hagfish!
我们绝不向亚特兰蒂斯屈膝
We will not bow to Atlantis.
我们给他们一仗  让他们永生难忘
We're gonna give them a fight that they will never forget!
不  我们需要他
No! We need him!
顺者昌  逆者亡
Join me or die.
你想让我称你为陛下吗
You expect me to address you as Your Highness?
不是"陛下"
Not Your Highness.
叫我...
Call me...
海洋领主
Ocean Master.
尽管把我的军队带走吧  你个软腹鼻涕虫
You can take my army, you soft-bellied slug.
但你休想让我对你效忠
But you will never have my allegiance!
那就这样吧
So be it!
搞什么...
What the...
真正的国王崛起了
The king has risen.
进攻
Attack!
伤亡太多了  我们必须马上停止战斗
There are too many casualties. We have to stop the fighting now.
我会找到我父亲  但你必须打败奥姆
I'll find my father. But you must defeat Orm.
如果我无法打败他呢
And what if I can't?
上次是他占尽天时地利
Last time, he was in his element.
这次  让他尝尝你拥有天时地利时的厉害
This time, make him fight in yours.
- 计划是什么来着  - 计划是不要被杀死
- What was the plan, again? -  The plan is to not get killed.
好计划  别被杀死
Yeah, good plan. Don't get killed.
海沟族  他号令了海沟族
The Trench! He commands the Trench!
不可能
Impossible!
退下  让她通过
Stand down! Let her pass.
父亲  求你了  他有三叉戟
Please, Father, he has the trident.
我知道你认为这场战争没必要
I know you think this war is necessary,
但按照我们最神圣的法典  亚瑟是国王
but Arthur is king by our most sacred law.
如果你现在无视那一点
And if you turn your back on that now,
那你守卫的亚特兰蒂斯就已经死了
then the Atlantis you're fighting for is already dead.
是真的
It's true!
那个杂种挥着亚特兰王的三叉戟
The half-breed wields King Atlan's trident.
他号令了大海
He commands the sea!
那那个混血种就是你们的国王了
Then that half-breed is your king.
维科  快来  他需要我们的帮助
Vulko! Come on, he needs our help!
我们不能去  你看
We can't! Look.
人民必须亲眼见证
The people must bear witness.
那把三叉戟不会改变你的出身
That trident doesn't change what you are.
你是个混血杂种
A half-breed bastard.
亚特兰蒂斯永远不会接受你成为其国王
Atlantis will never accept you as its king.
那浴血
Well, then by bloodshed...
方能明神意
Do the gods make known their will.
交出王位  交出来
Yield the throne. Yield it!
了结吧
Finish it.
交出王位
Yield the throne.
我们从不仁慈
Mercy is not our way.
你可能没注意到  弟弟
Maybe you haven't noticed, brother...
但我不是你们的一员
But I'm not one of you.
动手
Do it!
- 杀了我  - 不
- Kill me! -  No!
杀戮已经够多了
That is enough killing.
母亲
Mother?
我的儿子
Oh, my son.
说来话长了
It's a long story.
我晚点再告诉你
I'll tell ya later.
来吧
Come on!
我不明白  我们以为...
I don't understand. We thought...
我知道
I know.
亚瑟救了我
Arthur saved me.
- 你支持他  - 是的
- You're with him? -  I am.
你们都是我的孩子  我非常爱你们
You're both my children, and I love you so much.
但你被误导了
But you have been misguided.
你父亲教你说有两个世界
Your father taught you that there were two worlds.
但他错了
He was wrong.
陆地和海洋
The land and the sea
是一体的
are one.
我的王后
My queen.
维科
Vulko.
带他走
Take him.
但确保他能看到
But make sure he has a view.
等你准备好
When you're ready,
我们聊聊
let's talk.
亚特兰蒂斯人民  今天以流血开始
People of Atlantis, today began in bloodshed,
但我们以喜悦结束吧
but let it end in joy.
我为大家介绍亚特兰蒂斯亚瑟国王
I give you King Arthur of Atlantis.
国王万岁
Hail to the king!
- 国王万岁  - 国王万岁
- Hail to the king! -  Hail to the king!
现在我该怎么做
So, what do I do now?
当他们的国王
Be their king.
肯定会很好玩
This is gonna be fun.
你回来了  你回来了
You came back. You're back.
是的  是的
Yes. Yes.
我父亲是个灯塔管理员
My father was a lighthouse keeper.
我母亲是个王后
My mother was a queen.
他们不该相识...
They were never meant to meet...
但他们的爱拯救了世界
But their love saved the world.
他们造就了今天的我
They made me what I am.
陆地人的儿子  海洋的国王
A son of the land, and a king of the seas.
我是深海的保护者
I am the protector of the deep.
我是
I am...
海王
Aquaman.
我有15年
I spent 15 years
是在美国海洋科学研究所...
at the United States Institute of Marine Science...
- 你不是被炒了吗  - 研究海洋事件
- Weren't you fired? -  ...studying oceanic phenomenon,
这是目前为止最确凿的证据
and this is the most conclusive evidence we have to date.
深海地震仪
Deep-sea seismographs
记录到了海洋底部的爆炸
have recorded explosions on the ocean floor.
有卫星影像显示
We have satellite imagery
亚特兰蒂斯战舰碎片漂浮在海面...
of debris from Atlantean warships floating on the surface...
- 沈博士  - 你能让我说完吗
- Dr. Shin! -  Will you please let me finish?
又来了  亚特兰蒂斯
Here we go again. Atlantean?
对  政府不想让我们知道
Yes. The government does not want us to know
当前存在的威胁...
about the threat that exists right here...
我不建议你那么做
Yeah, I wouldn't do that if I were you.
这是亚特兰蒂斯人的技术  是吗
This is Atlantean technology, isn't it?
你能告诉我你怎么得到这个的吗
Can you tell me how you got this?
可以  但首先
Sure. But first,
你得告诉我怎么找到他
you gotta tell me how to find him.
(谁是海王)